<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Deployment on PositionPal</title><link>https://position-pal.github.io/docs/8-deployment/</link><description>Recent content in Deployment on PositionPal</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://position-pal.github.io/docs/8-deployment/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Deployment</title><link>https://position-pal.github.io/docs/8-deployment/deployment/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://position-pal.github.io/docs/8-deployment/deployment/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="deployment">Deployment &lt;a href="#deployment" class="anchor" aria-hidden="true">&lt;i class="material-icons align-middle">link&lt;/i>&lt;/a>&lt;/h1>&lt;p>Since our system is composed of multiple microservices, we decided to deploy it on a &lt;strong>Kubernetes cluster&lt;/strong>. Kubernetes is an open-source platform designed to automate deploying, scaling, and operating application containers. It is a powerful tool that allows us to manage our microservices in a more efficient way.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In particular the system is mapped on the main abstractions tha kubernetes provides:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Deployment&lt;/strong>: A Deployment is a higher-level API object that manages the execution of a set of pods. It provides declarative updates to applications, such as rolling updates, scaling, and pausing and resuming processes.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Service&lt;/strong>: A Service is a resource that provides a stable network endpoint for accessing a set of pods. It acts as an abstraction layer that routes traffic to the appropriate pods, even as pods are created, destroyed, or moved around the cluster. In our cluster we have two types of services: &lt;code>ClusterIP&lt;/code> and &lt;code>LoadBalancer&lt;/code>.
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>ClusterIP&lt;/strong>: Exposes the service on a cluster-internal IP. Choosing this value makes the service only reachable from within the cluster.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>LoadBalancer&lt;/strong>: Exposes the service externally using a cloud provider&amp;rsquo;s load balancer.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>Kubernetes also allows to define other resources that can be used to configure data usage inside the cluster:&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>