<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Architectural Design on PositionPal</title><link>https://position-pal.github.io/docs/3-arch-design/</link><description>Recent content in Architectural Design on PositionPal</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://position-pal.github.io/docs/3-arch-design/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Bounded Contexts</title><link>https://position-pal.github.io/docs/3-arch-design/1-bounded-contexts/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://position-pal.github.io/docs/3-arch-design/1-bounded-contexts/</guid><description>&lt;p>Following the event storming session, the subsequent bounded contexts have been identified:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Users Management&lt;/strong>: it is responsible for managing the users&amp;rsquo; lifecycle, from registration to deletion and the management of their profile information along with the authentication and authorization.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Groups Management&lt;/strong>: it is responsible for managing the groups&amp;rsquo; lifecycle, from creation to deletion, and the management of the group&amp;rsquo;s members.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Location Tracking&lt;/strong>: it is responsible for managing the location tracking of the users, including the sharing of the location with groups&amp;rsquo; members, the reception of location updates, thw sending of SOS alerts and the management of their paths.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Notifications&lt;/strong>: it is responsible for managing the notifications, including the push notifications to the users&amp;rsquo; devices.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Chat&lt;/strong>: it is responsible for managing the chat between the users and the groups&amp;rsquo; members.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>In the following sections, we will provide a detailed view of each bounded context, including its &lt;strong>&lt;em>Ubiquitous Language&lt;/em>&lt;/strong>, the &lt;strong>&lt;em>Commands&lt;/em>&lt;/strong> and the &lt;strong>&lt;em>Events&lt;/em>&lt;/strong> guiding the interactions between the different contexts.
These can be categorized as &lt;strong>&lt;em>Driving&lt;/em>&lt;/strong> or &lt;strong>&lt;em>Driven Events&lt;/em>&lt;/strong>: the former are the events triggered by the user&amp;rsquo;s actions and that drives an application use case, while the latter are the events that are triggered by the system as a reaction to a use case or a system state change.
Moreover we distinguish between &lt;em>Commands&lt;/em> and &lt;em>Events&lt;/em> to highlight the difference between a request to perform an action (&lt;em>Command&lt;/em>) and the notification of something meaningful that has happened (&lt;em>Event&lt;/em>):&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Architecture Design</title><link>https://position-pal.github.io/docs/3-arch-design/2-architecture-design/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://position-pal.github.io/docs/3-arch-design/2-architecture-design/</guid><description>&lt;p>The chosen architectural style for the system is the &lt;strong>Microservices Architecture&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;code>TODO: why, advantages&lt;/code>&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="microservices-decomposition">Microservices Decomposition &lt;a href="#microservices-decomposition" class="anchor" aria-hidden="true">&lt;i class="material-icons align-middle">link&lt;/i>&lt;/a>&lt;/h2>&lt;p>Following the &lt;em>decompose by subdomain strategy&lt;/em> the following microservices have been identified:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>User Service&lt;/strong>: responsible for managing the user account data and the groups of the system;&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Location Service&lt;/strong>: responsible for managing the location and the user tracking;&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Notification Service&lt;/strong>: responsible for managing the notifications;&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Chat Service&lt;/strong>: responsible for managing the chat messages.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>It should be noted that in the &lt;em>User Service&lt;/em> we have joined together the Users and Groups bounded context.
This is because one can see the close interaction between these two domain entities in addition to respecting properties such as the &amp;ldquo;Common Closure Principle&amp;rdquo; (package components that change for the same reason are located into the same service), ensuring data consistency and mitigate Network latency:&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Architectural Patterns</title><link>https://position-pal.github.io/docs/3-arch-design/4-patterns/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://position-pal.github.io/docs/3-arch-design/4-patterns/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="api-gateway">API Gateway &lt;a href="#api-gateway" class="anchor" aria-hidden="true">&lt;i class="material-icons align-middle">link&lt;/i>&lt;/a>&lt;/h2>&lt;h2 id="event-sourcing">Event Sourcing &lt;a href="#event-sourcing" class="anchor" aria-hidden="true">&lt;i class="material-icons align-middle">link&lt;/i>&lt;/a>&lt;/h2>&lt;h2 id="json-web-token-jwt">JSON Web Token (JWT) &lt;a href="#json-web-token-jwt" class="anchor" aria-hidden="true">&lt;i class="material-icons align-middle">link&lt;/i>&lt;/a>&lt;/h2>&lt;h2 id="cqrs-forse">CQRS forse? &lt;a href="#cqrs-forse" class="anchor" aria-hidden="true">&lt;i class="material-icons align-middle">link&lt;/i>&lt;/a>&lt;/h2>&lt;h2 id="deployment">Deployment? &lt;a href="#deployment" class="anchor" aria-hidden="true">&lt;i class="material-icons align-middle">link&lt;/i>&lt;/a>&lt;/h2></description></item></channel></rss>